片名：梦幻成真
先父名叫约翰康斯拉
My father's name was John Kinsella.
这是个爱尔兰名字
It's an Irish name.
他于1896年出生在北达科他州
He was born in North Dakota in 1896
在1918年从法国回来以前 从没见过大城市
and never saw a big city until he came back from France in 1918.
后来他定居芝加哥
Settling in Chicago, he learned to live and die
没多久就让白袜职棒队 控制了他的喜怒哀乐
with the White Sox.
当他们输了1919年的 世界大赛时，他有些不悦
Died a little when they lost the 1919 World Series,
“我们是诈输的” 但是到了夏天
died a lot when eight White Sox were accused of throwing that Series.
“两名白袜队球员坦承” 当八名球员
“我们是诈输的” 但是到了夏天
died a lot when eight White Sox were accused of throwing that Series.
被指控故意输球时 他的心碎了
He played some in the minors, but nothing came of it.
他在小联盟打了一、两年的棒球 可惜没多大发展
被指控故意输球时 他的心碎了
He played some in the minors, but nothing came of it.
他在小联盟打了一、两年的棒球 可惜没多大发展
在三十五岁时搬到布鲁克林
Moved to Brooklyn in '35, married Mom in '38,
他在小联盟打了一、两年的棒球 可惜没多大发展
在三十五岁时搬到布鲁克林
Moved to Brooklyn in '35, married Mom in '38,
三十八岁和母亲结婚
was already an old man at the naval yards
我在1952年出生
when I was born in 1952.
那时他已经是个 在海军工场工作的老人
我在1952年出生
when I was born in 1952.
那时他已经是个 在海军工场工作的老人
我的名字是瑞康斯拉
My name's Ray Kinsella.
那时他已经是个 在海军工场工作的老人
我的名字是瑞康斯拉
My name's Ray Kinsella.
三岁时母亲过逝，而我…
Mom died when I was three, and I suppose Dad did the best he could.
我想父亲 的确尽了他最大的努力
Instead of Mother Goose, I was put to bed to stories of Babe Ruth,
每晚的睡前故事不是鹅妈妈
我想父亲 的确尽了他最大的努力
Instead of Mother Goose, I was put to bed to stories of Babe Ruth,
“名棒球选手” 而是贝比鲁斯、贾里格
Lou Gehrig, and the great Shoeless Joe Jackson.
以及伟大的“赤脚乔”杰克森
“名棒球选手” 而是贝比鲁斯、贾里格
Lou Gehrig, and the great Shoeless Joe Jackson.
以及伟大的“赤脚乔”杰克森
Dad was a Yankees fan then, so I rooted for Brooklyn.
父亲是纽约洋基队的球迷 而我则替布鲁克林道奇队加油
但是在1958年道奇队搬走了
In '58, the Dodgers moved away, so we had to find other reasons to fight.
父亲是纽约洋基队的球迷 而我则替布鲁克林道奇队加油
但是在1958年道奇队搬走了
In '58, the Dodgers moved away, so we had to find other reasons to fight.
我们又得找别的话题来争执
但是在1958年道奇队搬走了
In '58, the Dodgers moved away, so we had to find other reasons to fight.
我们又得找别的话题来争执
也的确找到了
We did.
我们又得找别的话题来争执
也的确找到了
We did.
到了选大学的时候
When I chose a college,
我选了离家最远的学校
I picked the farthest from home I could find.
“柏克莱大学” 这当然让他火冒三丈
This drove him up the wall, which, I suppose, was the point.
其实是我故意这么做的
“柏克莱大学” 这当然让他火冒三丈
This drove him up the wall, which, I suppose, was the point.
其实是我故意这么做的
当时我主修英文
Officially, my major was English, but really, it was the '60s.
其实是我故意这么做的
当时我主修英文
Officially, my major was English, but really, it was the '60s.
但是别忘了，那是六零年代
I marched, I smoked some grass,
“做爱不作战” 我示威游行过，也抽过大麻
I tried to like sitar music, and I met Annie.
更试着接受西塔琴音乐 后来遇到了安妮
“做爱不作战” 我示威游行过，也抽过大麻
I tried to like sitar music, and I met Annie.
更试着接受西塔琴音乐 后来遇到了安妮
我们唯一的共同点是 她来自爱荷华
The only thing we had in common
更试着接受西塔琴音乐 后来遇到了安妮
我们唯一的共同点是 她来自爱荷华
The only thing we had in common
was that she came from Iowa, and I'd once heard of Iowa.
而我曾经听过爱荷华
毕业后，我们搬到中西部去
After graduation, we moved to the Midwest
而我曾经听过爱荷华
毕业后，我们搬到中西部去
After graduation, we moved to the Midwest
至于和她家人 相处的最大极限是…
and stayed with her family as long as we could,
一个下午
almost a full afternoon.
我们在1974年的六月结婚
Annie and I got married in June of '74.
父亲就在那年的秋天去世
Dad died that fall.
几年后，凯伦诞生了
A few years later, Karin was born.
虽然闻起来怪怪的 但我们仍然深爱着她
She smelled weird, but we loved her anyway.
后来安妮发了奇想 居然说服我买下一座农场
Then Annie got the crazy idea she could talk me into buying a farm.
我现在三十六岁 热爱我的家人和棒球
I'm 36 years old, I love my family,
I love baseball, and I'm about to become a farmer.
“已出售” 而我即将成为一个农夫
但我必须澄清一点
But until I heard the voice,
“已出售” 而我即将成为一个农夫
但我必须澄清一点
But until I heard the voice,
在听到那个声音之前 我从没做过疯狂的事
I'd never done a crazy thing in my whole life.
如果你盖了，他就会来
If you build it, he will come.
喂，安妮
Hey, Annie!
那是什么？ 你在说什么？
Annie, what was that?
What was what?
刚才的声音到底是什么意思？
That voice just now. What was it?
我们没听到任何声音
We didn't hear anything.
好吧
All right.
如果你盖了，他就会来
If you build it, he will come.
你现在总该听到了吧
Okay, you must have heard that!
还是没有，进来吃晚饭啦
Sorry. Hey, come on in to dinner.
Let's go, pumpkin.
公路上是不是有扩音器？
Is there, like, a sound truck on the highway?
没有
Nope. Hey, Karin, dinner's ready!
凯伦，来吃饭啦
没有
Nope. Hey, Karin, dinner's ready!
凯伦，来吃饭啦
有没有小孩在听收音机？ 没有
Kids with a radio?
凯伦，来吃饭啦
有没有小孩在听收音机？ 没有
Kids with a radio?
Nope.
你真的听到声音？
Hey, are you really hearing voices?
只听到一次
Just one.
说什么？
What did it say?
“如果你盖了，他就会来”
"If you build it, he will come."
盖什么、谁会来呢？
If you build what, who will come?
他没说
He didn't say.
我最讨厌这样子 我也是
I hate it when that happens.
Me, too.
如果你盖了，他就会来
If you build it, he will come.
盖什么？这到底是什么意思 瑞
Build what? What is this?
Ray?
别担心，没事的
It's okay, honey. I... I'm just talking to the cornfield.
我只是在和玉米田讲话
别担心，没事的
It's okay, honey. I... I'm just talking to the cornfield.
我只是在和玉米田讲话
好啦，当我在走路的时候
Anyway, I was walking down along the street,
and I heard this voice saying,
听到一个声音说 “陶先生，晚安”
"Good evening, Mr. Dowd."
我一转身…
Well, I turned around,
and here was this big, six-foot rabbit leaning up against the lamppost.
就看见一只六尺高的兔子 依着街灯的柱子
你为什么要关掉，很好玩的
Why did you do that? It was funny.
相信我，一点也不好玩 那个人有病，而且病得不轻
Trust me, Karin. It's not funny.
The man is sick. Very sick.
凯伦，吃完了就去拿书包 我们得走了
Karin, honey, get your book bag. Let's go!
今天我带她上学好了
Hon, I'll take her today.
我得进城买点东西
I've got errands to do in town.
太好了
Far out.
Hey. What if the voice calls while you're gone?
如果那声音又出现 我该怎么办？
就记下来吧      拜拜
Take a message.
Bye.
再见      再见
这些年中，你有没有…
In all those years, did you ever...
有人告诉我在田里工作时
It's just I've heard that sometimes farmers in the field...
有时会听到奇怪的声音
They hear things. You know, voices.
你听到声音了？ 不是，是别人这么说的
You hearing voices?
No. It's just I heard some farmers do.
我当然没听过
I, of course, don't, so I was wondering if I was doing something wrong.
所以我在想 是不是我哪里做错了
我当然没听过
I, of course, don't, so I was wondering if I was doing something wrong.
所以我在想 是不是我哪里做错了
你有没有听到过声音？ 谁听到声音？
Did you... Did you ever hear voices out there?
Who's hearing voices?
是瑞…在田里面
Ray is.
Out in the fields. No, I'm not.
我没有
I'm...
是噪音
Noises. That darned tractor...
那些牵引机的声…
是噪音
Noises. That darned tractor...
那些牵引机的声…
我只要再买点油就行了
I'm just going to get some 3-in-1 oil. That ought to do it.
那些牵引机的声…
我只要再买点油就行了
I'm just going to get some 3-in-1 oil. That ought to do it.
It was nice... Nice talking to you.
和你们…谈话很愉快
如果你盖了，他就会来
If you build it, he will come.
好了，够啦，你他妈…
All right, that's it! Who the...
你是谁，到底想干嘛？ 真是活见鬼了
Who are you? What do you want from me?
Son of a...
如果你盖了，他就会来
If you build it, he will come.
If you build it...
如果你盖了
If you build it,
he will come.
他就会来
你确定不是迷幻药产生的幻觉
You don't suppose this is like an acid flashback, do you?
我从没吃过迷幻药
I never took acid.
也许那是 预言你将来会吃迷幻药
Maybe you will someday. It's like a flash-forward.
安妮，我想不止如此 宝贝，再多吃点
Annie, there's more.
Honey, why don't you eat a little bit?
I... I think I know what "If you build it, he will come" means.
我大概已经知道“如果你盖了 他就会来”的意思了
哦，我有种不好的预感
Why do I not think this is so good?
我大概已经知道“如果你盖了 他就会来”的意思了
哦，我有种不好的预感
Why do I not think this is so good?
它的意思是 如果我在田里盖个棒球场
I think it means that if I build a baseball field out there,
那么赤脚乔杰克森就会来打球
Shoeless Joe Jackson will get to come back and play ball again.
你在开玩笑
You're kidding?
没有
哇！      对呀
Yeah.
You're kidding.
你一定在开玩笑
我一直以为我的家人够另类
Boy, I thought my family was crazy, but this is the craziest thing ever.
没想到你比他们还厉害
I know. It's totally nuts. I mean, Shoeless Joe!
我知道听起来像胡说八道 你要知道赤脚乔…
没想到你比他们还厉害
I know. It's totally nuts. I mean, Shoeless Joe!
我知道听起来像胡说八道 你要知道赤脚乔…
已是一堆枯骨了 他死于1951年
He's dead. Died in '51. He's dead.
我知道听起来像胡说八道 你要知道赤脚乔…
已是一堆枯骨了 他死于1951年
He's dead. Died in '51. He's dead.
当初他被迫离开棒球队吗？ 没错
They suspended him, right?
Right.
他并没有复活吧？ 就我所知没有
He's still dead?
As far as I know.
你知道 贝比鲁斯就是学他的挥棒动作
Did you know Babe Ruth copied his swing?
就算知道也忘了
If I did, I've forgotten it.
他的挥棒是那么的优雅和敏捷
He was supposed to be so graceful and agile.
若能再看到他打棒球…
I'd actually like to see him play again,
能让他再打球，并替他洗雪…
to let him play, to right an old wrong.
等一等
Wait. Wait a minute, Bosco.
你真要盖个棒球场？
Are you actually thinking of doing this?
No.
我实在找不出理由去盖它 但是…
I mean, I can't think of one good reason why I should, but...
我已经三十六岁，有妻、有女 还有房屋贷款
I'm 36. I have a wife, a child, and a mortgage,
但我深怕 会步上我父亲的后尘
and I'm scared to death I'm turning into my father.
这和你父亲又有什么关系
What's your father got to do with all of this?
我永远不能原谅他的老去
I never forgave him for getting old.
当他在我现在这个年纪
By the time he was as old as I am now, he was ancient.
已经老得动不了
他一定也有过梦想
I mean, he must have had dreams, but he never did anything about them.
可惜没法去实现
他一定也有过梦想
I mean, he must have had dreams, but he never did anything about them.
可惜没法去实现
我猜他也曾听到过声音
For all I know, he may have even heard voices, too,
可惜没法去实现
我猜他也曾听到过声音
For all I know, he may have even heard voices, too,
but he sure didn't listen to them.
却从来没有驻足倾听过
就我所知 他从没做过率性而为的事
The man never did one spontaneous thing in all the years I knew him.
却从来没有驻足倾听过
就我所知 他从没做过率性而为的事
The man never did one spontaneous thing in all the years I knew him.
我不愿和他一样
Annie, I'm afraid of that happening to me,
在心灵的深处我感觉得到 这将是最后的机会了
and something tells me this may be my last chance to do something about it.
我要盖个棒球场
I want to build that field.
你说我疯了吗？
Do you think I'm crazy?
是疯了
Yes.
可是我也觉得…
But I also think if you really feel you should do this,
如果你真有这种感觉
可是我也觉得…
But I also think if you really feel you should do this,
如果你真有这种感觉
那就应该全力以赴
then you should do it.
他在搞什么鬼？
What the hell is he doing?
铲除玉米田呀      为什么？
He's plowing under his corn.
Why?
泰柯布被称为 史上最伟大的外野手
Ty Cobb called him the greatest left fielder of all time.
他是见球就封
He said his glove was the place where triples go to die.
他能击球吗？ “他能击球吗？”
- Could he hit? - Could he hit?
他平均打击率是零点三五六 是史上第三高的
Lifetime average. 356, third highest in history.
为什么叫他赤脚乔？
Why'd they call him Shoeless Joe?
因为在他刚出道的时候 买了一双钉鞋
When he was still in the minors,
he bought a new pair of spikes and hurt his feet.
可是穿久了脚会痛 所以在第六局的时候
In the sixth inning, he took them off and played in his socks.
他就把鞋脱下来 穿着袜子打完全场
可是穿久了脚会痛 所以在第六局的时候
In the sixth inning, he took them off and played in his socks.
他就把鞋脱下来 穿着袜子打完全场
其他球员 就戏称他为“赤脚乔”
The players kidded him,
他就把鞋脱下来 穿着袜子打完全场
其他球员 就戏称他为“赤脚乔”
The players kidded him,
called him "Shoeless Joe," and the name stuck.
后来这个外号就流行开来
He's going to lose his farm.
他一定保不住这个农场 真是个笨蛋
Damned fool.
Then in 1919, his team, the Chicago White Sox,
后来在1919年他的球队 就是芝加哥的白袜队
在世界大赛中诈输
they threw the World Series.
后来在1919年他的球队 就是芝加哥的白袜队
在世界大赛中诈输
they threw the World Series.
什么是“诈输”？ 就是有人付钱让他们故意输
What's "threw"?
It means they lost on purpose.
Gamblers paid them to. Except Shoeless Joe.
可是并不包括赤脚乔
He did take their money,
虽然他的确拿了钱
but nobody ever proved he did one thing to lose those games.
可是却找不出他有诈输的动作
虽然他的确拿了钱
but nobody ever proved he did one thing to lose those games.
可是却找不出他有诈输的动作
假如他真是故意输球
If he threw it,
how do you explain he hit .375 for the Series and committed no errors?
那怎么解释他那 完美无缺的零点三七五打击率
我不能   他打了十二枝安打
I can't.
那怎么解释他那 完美无缺的零点三七五打击率
我不能   他打了十二枝安打
I can't.
Twelve hits including the Series' only home run,
其中还包括全垒打
and they said he's trying to lose?
他们居然说他是故意输的？ 太莫名其妙了
It's ridiculous.
八名棒球员中包括赤脚乔在内
The commissioner of baseball suspended eight of the players,
全被棒球委员会判终生停职
including the great Shoeless Joe Jackson, for life.
什么是“终生停职”？
What's "suspend"?
就是终生不能再打棒球
It means they never let him play the game again.
据我父亲说
My father said he saw him years later
后来他曾在卡州的烂球场中 见到赤脚乔以化名在打球
playing under a made-up name in some 10th-rate league in Carolina.
当时他臃肿肥胖完全没有活力
He'd put on 50 pounds, and his spring was gone from his step
但仍能击出安打
but he could still hit.
我爸爸常说 赤脚乔的打击举世无双
Dad used to say nobody could hit like Shoeless Joe.
你知道当你说到你父亲时
I think that's the first time I've ever seen you smile
这是第一次你脸上有了笑容
when you mentioned your father.
好了…
Well...
我做了件完全不合逻辑的事
I have just created something totally illogical.
我就喜欢这点
That's what I like about it.
我是不是彻底的疯了？
Am I completely nuts?
并不完全
Not completely.
那是座很好的棒球场
It's a good baseball field, Ray.
而且还挺漂亮的   嗯
It's kind of pretty, isn't it?
有迹象吗？
Any sign?
马上就会有事发生了
Something's going to happen out there.
我能感觉得到
I can feel it.
对一个有经验的左投手
So, for the veteran southpaw, his summer of woes continues.
他的不幸仍然持续着
That's four straight hits in the inning.
那是这局的第四支安打
Daddy, what's a "southpaw"?
爹地，什么是“左投手”？
那是这局的第四支安打
Daddy, what's a "southpaw"?
爹地，什么是“左投手”？
就是用左手投球的投手
It means a left-handed pitcher, honey.
到底有多糟？
So how bad is it?
少了好几亩玉米田的收入
Well, considering how much less acreage we have for corn,
我估计…应该正好打平
I say we'll probably
almost break even.
我们把所有的储蓄全投下去了
We used up all our savings on that field, Ray.
爹地      凯伦等一下
Daddy?
Just a minute, Karin.
那你看棒球场能留吗？
So what are you saying? We can't keep the field?
留下的话可能连农场也保不住
Makes it real hard to keep the farm.
爹地   跟你说等一下嘛！
Daddy.
In a minute, Karin!
有个人在我们的新草坪上
There's a man out there on your lawn.
我去煮咖啡，你到外面去呀
I'll put up some coffee. Why don't you go on outside?
对不起
Sorry.
我会打些球给你
I'll get some out there.
我叫…瑞康斯拉
Hi.
Ray Kinsella.
我是乔杰克森
Joe Jackson.
能再打球的感觉一定很好
I bet it's good to be playing again?
自从被棒球委员会踢出去后
Getting thrown out of baseball
我整个人都瘫痪了
was like having part of me amputated.
我似乎听得到
I've heard that old men wake up
and scratch itchy legs that have been dust for over 50 years.
在五十年后 一个老人醒过来搔腿的声音
那就是我
That was me.
在五十年后 一个老人醒过来搔腿的声音
那就是我
That was me.
一天晚上我醒过来
I'd wake up at night
鼻子闻到了球场的芳香
with the smell of the ballpark in my nose,
with the cool of the grass on my feet,
脚下踩着冰凉的草地
那是一种惊喜
the thrill of the grass.
你能投球吗？
Can you pitch?
可以
Yeah,
而且还不错
not bad.
我们需要捕手吗？
Don't we need a catcher?
如果投在本垒板附近就不要
Not if you get it near the plate.
对
Right.
我正在投球给赤脚乔
I'm pitching to Shoeless Joe Jackson.
打得好
Nice hit.
试试我的曲球
See if you can hit my curve.
你还真能打曲球
You can hit the curve ball.
投到这里来
Put one right here?
好
Right.
对啦，你最擅长打低球
Right, you're a low ball hitter.
天呀，我真喜欢这个运动
Man, I did love this game.
就算拿吃饭钱来换，我也愿意
I'd have played for food money.
那种比赛时的…
It was the game,
喧闹声和草香，深深吸引着我
the sounds, the smells.
你有没有 把手套紧贴着脸的经验？
Did you ever hold a ball or a glove to your face?
有
Yeah.
我最喜欢坐火车 到不同城市去旅行
I used to love traveling on the trains from town to town.
像旅馆里…
The hotels,
大厅中的铜痰盂 和房间里的黄铜床
brass spittoons in the lobbies, brass beds in the rooms.
还有群众们…
It was the crowd,
看到好安打 就站起来欢呼的盛况
rising to their feet when the ball was hit deep.
说实话…
Shoot,
就算不付钱我也愿意打球
I'd have played for nothing.
那是我的家人
It's my family.
为什么要装灯？
What's with the lights?
All the stadiums have them now.
现在所有的球场都装了
Even Wrigley Field.
即使是最落伍的球场也有 这样不容易看到球
It's harder to see the ball.
都是那些老板们认为 晚上来看球赛的人会比较多
The owners found that more people can attend night games.
真拿他们没办法
Owners.
杰克森先生，这是我太太安妮 还有我女儿凯伦
Mr. Jackson, this is my wife Annie and my daughter Karin.
女士们好
Ma'am. Hi.
你是鬼吗？
Are you a ghost?
凯伦
Karin.
她在开玩笑 没关系，你说呢？
She's kidding.
That's okay.
What do you think?
你看起来很真实
You look real to me.
那么我就是真的啰
Then I guess I'm real.
请到里面坐坐
Would you like to come inside?
噢，谢谢，我不能进去
Thanks. I don't think I can.
我能再来吗？
Can I come back again?
当然可以，这是为你盖的
Yeah. I built this for you.
你知道还有其他的人
There are others, you know.
我们一共有八个人 他们会很感激的
There were eight of us. It would really mean a lot to them.
没问题 任何时间都欢迎你们来
Yeah, anytime. They're all welcome here.
嘿，这是天堂吗？
Hey, is this heaven?
不是
No.
是爱荷华州
It's Iowa.
他要去哪里？ 不知道
Where's he going?
I don't know.
我们一定要保住棒球场
We're keeping this field.
就算拼命也要留住它
You bet your ass we are.
你会把农场给丢了 少来啦
You're going to lose your farm, pal.
它这么大，怎么会丢呢
How can you lose something so big?
有一次他把房子放错地方 但是两天后又找到了
He misplaced the house once. Yeah, but it turned up.
对不对？
Ray, come on. Ray? Ray?
瑞，你别这样
This stupid baseball field's going to bankrupt you.
大家都看得出来 这个讨厌的棒球场会拖垮你
瑞，你别这样
This stupid baseball field's going to bankrupt you.
大家都看得出来 这个讨厌的棒球场会拖垮你
我只想提醒你 如果拖欠贷款你就会失去一切
If you default on your loan, you're going to lose everything.
大家都看得出来 这个讨厌的棒球场会拖垮你
我只想提醒你 如果拖欠贷款你就会失去一切
If you default on your loan, you're going to lose everything.
最好卖给我的合伙人 他会给你个好价钱，你就能…
My partners will give you a fair price.
马克，谢谢你，但是我不卖
Thanks, Mark. Thanks, Mark, but no.
不卖      好吧
No.
那我问你，为什么要待在这里
What are you holding onto this place for?
你从没喜欢过爱荷华州
You never liked Iowa.
你胡说      少装了
That's not true.
你根本不喜欢耕作 而且对农事一无所知
You don't know the first thing about farming.
我知道的不少   是吗？
I know a lot about farming. More than you think.
比你想像的要多
Well, then how could you plow under your major crop?
那你怎么会铲除你的庄稼呢
比你想像的要多
Well, then how could you plow under your major crop?
那你怎么会铲除你的庄稼呢
什么是庄稼？
What's a crop?
好啦，别吵了
Come on. That is funny. What's a crop?
什么是庄稼？
Daddy, the baseball game is on.
爹地，球赛要开始了 失陪一下
什么是庄稼？
Daddy, the baseball game is on.
爹地，球赛要开始了 失陪一下
Excuse us.
我们先走一步
安妮，我真不敢相信这家伙
Annie, I don't believe this guy.
我想救他，他却跑去看电视
I'm trying to bail him out, and he leaves to watch television.
他以前还蛮正常的嘛 是呀
He used to be normal. Yeah.
Buck!
All right.
Hoy! Hoy! Hoy!
好，回本垒
All right! Home base!
注意乔，看着他的脚
Watch Joe's feet.
当投手收到信号准备投球时
A good left fielder knows what pitch is coming.
好的左外野手就能从…
He can tell from the bat's angle which way the ball's heading.
球棒和球接触的角度 而测知球的方向
好的左外野手就能从…
He can tell from the bat's angle which way the ball's heading.
球棒和球接触的角度 而测知球的方向
耶！
又在耍酷了 甘德，你少在嘴上逞能
Show off!
耶！
又在耍酷了 甘德，你少在嘴上逞能
Show off!
Stick it in your ear, Gandil.
对，在和底特律比赛的时候 你若能跑得那么快
If you'd have run like that against Detroit, I'd have won 20 games!
那一年我们至少能赢二十场
对，在和底特律比赛的时候 你若能跑得那么快
If you'd have run like that against Detroit, I'd have won 20 games!
那一年我们至少能赢二十场
天呀，那是六十八年前的老帐 拜托别提了
For Pete's sakes, Cicotte, that was 68 years ago.
那一年我们至少能赢二十场
天呀，那是六十八年前的老帐 拜托别提了
For Pete's sakes, Cicotte, that was 68 years ago.
Give it up!
Hey! You guys want to play ball or what?
喂，你们到底要不要玩球
肌肉僵硬的混球
Muscle-bound jerk.
喂，你们到底要不要玩球
肌肉僵硬的混球
Muscle-bound jerk.
哼，至少我还有肌肉
At least I got muscles.
不，你是四肢发达
At most you got muscles.
你又在放屁，快投球
Come on, asshole! Pitch!
别说脏话呀
Weaver, be nice.
对不起
Sorry, kid!
没关系，我不介意
It's okay. I don't mind.
All right, Karin.
Hey, hey, hey!
Ray? Honey, Mom and everybody's leaving now.
老公，妈妈他们要走了
Okay.
你们能来是…谢谢你们来
Well, it was... You know.
Thanks for coming.
瑞，考虑一下我的话 我只想帮忙而已
Ray, think about what I said. I'm just trying to help.
我知道
I know.
你们不是要看球赛吗？
Thought you two were watching some game.
恐怕他们只能练球了
It's not really a game. It's more like practice.
你看他们只有八个人 所以不能比赛
There's only eight of them. They can't play a real game.
八个什么？
Eight of what?
他们呀
Them.
谁呀？      就是他们嘛
Who them? Them them.
难道你看不到他们？ 凯伦，你在看什么？
You don't see them?
Karin, honey, what are you watching?
打棒球的人呀
The baseball men.
Baseball men?
你看得到打棒球的人？
Do you see the baseball men right now?
当然看得到
Of course I do.
你真的看不到他们？
What, you really don't see them?
这种愚弄人的态度很不礼貌
It's not very polite to try to make other people feel stupid.
妈，等等，等一下嘛！
Mom, wait a minute. Mom! Wait a minute.
狄，你真看不到那些人？
Dee. Dee, wait. You don't see these people?
安妮，一点也不好玩
It's not funny, Annie.
他们居然看不到他们
They couldn't see it.
这实在很有趣
This is really interesting.
嘿，瑞，你看看
Hey, Ray, look at this.
我穿这件制服已经六十八年了 仍旧这么合身
Sixty-eight years since I wore this uniform, still fits me like a glove.
那你一定时常锻炼身体
You must keep in pretty good shape.
我在1970年代死的
Now let's see, I died in '70.
这表示我有十八年没碰过香烟
That means I haven't had a cigarette in 18 years.
你不抽烟吧      不抽
You don't smoke, do you?
No.
凯伦、瑞…
Karin! Ray! Dinner!
晚餐好了！
"Ray, dinner." "Dinner, Ray."
瑞，吃晚餐了      吃饭了，瑞
晚餐好了！
"Ray, dinner." "Dinner, Ray."
瑞，吃晚餐了      吃饭了，瑞
All right, all right.
好啦，别闹了
Come on. Let's hit the showers.
走吧，我们去洗澡      等会见
See you later.
再见
See you, guys.
我快融化了
I'm melting! I'm melting!
Come on, you knucklehead.
哇，真酷！
That is so cool.
抚平他的伤痛
Ease his pain.
什么？
What?
对不起，我没听懂
I'm sorry. What? I didn't understand. What?
抚平他的伤痛
Ease his pain.
抚平他的伤痛？ 天呀，这又是什么意思？
Ease his pain. What...
What the hell does that mean, ease his pain?
什么伤痛？是谁的伤痛？
What pain? All right. Whose pain?
多谢你啦
Thanks a lot.
快去洗个澡 晚饭后得去参加家长会
Come on, honey, wash up. We got the PTA meeting after dinner.
他们又想禁书了
Talking about banning books again, really subversive books,
就是禁所谓有破坏性的书 像绿野仙踪、安妮的日记之类
like The Wizard of Oz, Diary of Anne Frank.
你怎么搞的？      声音又来了
What happened to you?
The voice is back.
这次总不会要你盖个足球场吧
You don't have to build a football field, do you?
他说“抚平他的伤痛”
He said, "Ease his pain."
谁的伤痛？ 我问了，他不肯说
Ease whose pain?
I asked him. He wouldn't say.
是赤脚乔的？      我想不是
Shoeless Joe's?
I don't think so.
其他球员的？      也不是
One of the other players?
I don't think so.
你听到的那个声音 太莫测高深啦
This is a very nonspecific voice out there, and he's starting to piss me off.
真快把我搞火了
你听到的那个声音 太莫测高深啦
This is a very nonspecific voice out there, and he's starting to piss me off.
真快把我搞火了
今天本来很愉快的
I was having a fun day today, a good day.
要吃炸薯条吗？
Want a fry?
我认为这么淫秽的书
And I say, smut and filth like this has
绝不能出现在学校里
no place in our schools.
这个法西斯党徒 我真想去抚平她的伤痛
Fascist. I'd like to ease her pain.
Mrs. Kessinik, Mrs. Kessinik.
戚太太，你手里所挥的书 一点也不淫秽
That book you're waving about is hardly smut.
实际上，许多评论家…
It's considered by many critics to be the classic novel about the 1960s.
视它为六零年代的经典小说
It's pornography!
它是色情书刊 不，最高法院说…
No, no. The Supreme Court says it's not.
不是
And it's author, Mr. Mann... Is sick!
而且作者泰伦斯孟…
不是
And it's author, Mr. Mann... Is sick!
而且作者泰伦斯孟…
他有病！
Terence Mann is a Pulitzer Prize winner.
泰伦斯孟是普力兹奖的得主
He's widely regarded as the finest satirist of his time.
而且大家视他为 他那年代里最好的讽刺作家
泰伦斯孟是普力兹奖的得主
He's widely regarded as the finest satirist of his time.
而且大家视他为 他那年代里最好的讽刺作家
可是我觉得他很邪恶 恐怕是共产党徒
He's a pervert!
而且大家视他为 他那年代里最好的讽刺作家
可是我觉得他很邪恶 恐怕是共产党徒
He's a pervert!
Probably a Communist, too!
他们是来自哪个星球哟？
What planet are these people from?
哈先生，泰伦斯孟的那些小说
Mr. Harris, the so-called novels of Terence Mann
充满了乱交、无神论
endorse promiscuity, godlessness,
种族混杂
the mongrelization of the races,
而且轻蔑美国军队中的…
and disrespect to high-ranking officers of the United States Army.
“抚平他的伤痛” 高级军官
而且轻蔑美国军队中的…
and disrespect to high-ranking officers of the United States Army.
“抚平他的伤痛” 高级军官
所以全美国从1969年以来
And that's why right-thinking school boards all across the country
“抚平他的伤痛” 高级军官
所以全美国从1969年以来
And that's why right-thinking school boards all across the country
只要是思想健全的学校 早把他的书…
having been banning this man's S-H-I-T
给禁了！
since 1969.
泰伦斯孟？
Terence Mann?
你们知道他为什么不再写书吗
You know why he stopped writing books. Because he masturbates.
因为他手淫
你们知道他为什么不再写书吗
You know why he stopped writing books. Because he masturbates.
因为他手淫
女士，打扰一下
Excuse me, madam.
我想插句话
Excuse me.
在那一段疯狂的年代里
Terence Mann was a warm, gentle voice of reason
泰伦斯孟是一道清流
during a time of great madness.
当大家嘴里念着 “烧吧，努力烧吧”的时候
He coined the phrase, "Make love, not war."
他创造了 “做爱不作战”这句话
While other people were chanting, "Burn, baby, burn,"
他所谈的是爱、和平和了解
he was talking about love and peace and understanding.
我珍爱他每一本书
I cherished his books, and I dearly wish he had written more.
并且希望他能再多写一点
我珍爱他每一本书
I cherished his books, and I dearly wish he had written more.
并且希望他能再多写一点
如果你经历过六零年代 就算只碰到一点边
Maybe if you had experienced even a little bit of the '60s,
并且希望他能再多写一点
如果你经历过六零年代 就算只碰到一点边
Maybe if you had experienced even a little bit of the '60s,
也会和我有同样的想法
you might feel the same way, too.
我当然经历过六零年代
I experienced the '60s.
不，你是过了两个五零年 就直接跳到七零年
No, you had two '50s and moved right on into the '70s.
安妮，你看   喔，是吗？
Annie, look at this.
Your husband plowed under his corn and built a baseball field.
你先生居然发神经 铲了玉米田去盖棒球场
好，居然敢惹起我来啦
Now, there's an intelligent response.
他是个怪物
The weirdo.
Annie... Honey, it's all right. I'll be cool.
你放心，我会很冷静的
你这个纳粹猪，至少他不烧书
At least he is not a book burner, you Nazi cow.
你放心，我会很冷静的
你这个纳粹猪，至少他不烧书
At least he is not a book burner, you Nazi cow.
至少我先生没染上海洛因瘾
At least I'm not married to the biggest horse's ass in three counties.
好，你敢出去比划吗？
All right, Beulah, do you want to step outside?
出去就出去
Fine!
Annie.
坐下来   我没事
All right, honey. I've got a better idea.
我有个好主意 来投票表决，如何？
Let's take a vote. Who's for Eva Braun?
谁赞成希特勒之妻？
Who wants to burn books?
谁愿意去烧书？
谁赞成希特勒之妻？
Who wants to burn books?
谁愿意去烧书？
谁想反对美国宪法？
Who wants to spit on the Constitution of the United States of America? Anybody?
谁愿意去烧书？
谁想反对美国宪法？
Who wants to spit on the Constitution of the United States of America? Anybody?
有人吗？
谁想反对美国宪法？
Who wants to spit on the Constitution of the United States of America? Anybody?
有人吗？
好，谁赞成权力法案？
All right. Now, who's for the Bill of Rights?
谁认为自由是件好事？
Who thinks freedom is a pretty darn good thing?
来呀！同意的请举手
Come on! Come on! Let's see those hands!
谁认为我们应该从
Who thinks we have to stand up to the kind of censorship
史达林的审查制度中走出来？
they had under Stalin?
这才是真正的美国人
All right. There you go. America, I love you. I'm proud of you.
我爱你们、为你们感到骄傲 干什么？
这才是真正的美国人
All right. There you go. America, I love you. I'm proud of you.
我爱你们、为你们感到骄傲 干什么？
我们得走了 我们走了，真过瘾
Let's go. We got to go.
我爱你们、为你们感到骄傲 干什么？
我们得走了 我们走了，真过瘾
Let's go. We got to go.
This is great!
我想出来了
I figured it out. I figured it out.
你看我是不是很厉害？ 我终于想出来了
Was that great, or what? I figured it out.
就像又回到六零年代一样 我刚想出来的
It's just like the '60s again! I just figured it out.
“到外面去，你这只纳粹猪” 我知道去抚平谁的伤痛了
"Step outside, you Nazi cow."
I know whose pain I'm supposed to ease.
什么？ 我知道该去抚平谁的伤痛
What? I know whose pain I'm supposed to ease.
我才制止那些人在美国 散布法西斯思想，你却说…
I just halted the spread of neofascism in America...
泰伦斯孟
Terence Mann. What about him?
他怎么了？      就是他的伤痛
That's whose pain. You sure?
你怎么知道？ 说不上来，就是知道嘛
I was right about building the field, wasn't I?
当初盖球场还不是盖对了？
Well, what's his pain? I don't know.
没错，他有什么伤痛 我不知道
How are you supposed to ease it? I don't know.
那你要怎么去抚平呢？ 也不知道
Ray. Well, Ann...
他也是我最喜欢的作家
Look, he's my favorite writer, too,
但是他和棒球有什么关系？
but what's Terence Mann got to do with baseball?
“当我们最需要 泰伦斯孟的时候他在哪里？”
“纽约大学逮捕五名 静坐抗议者——泰伦斯孟被捕”
“20个有关美国 现存最伟大作家的传闻”
“普立兹奖”
Annie, it's incredible. By the early '70s,
在七零年代初
安妮，他真了不起
Mann decides people have become either too extremist
在七零年代初
安妮，他真了不起
Mann decides people have become either too extremist
他发觉人们对他的理论 不是太激进就是太冷淡
or too apathetic to listen.
So he stops writing books,
所以他停止写作
he starts writing poetry about whales,
而开始写些鲸鱼的诗词
所以他停止写作
he starts writing poetry about whales,
而开始写些鲸鱼的诗词
后来他迷上了家用电脑
and then he starts fooling around with a computer.
而开始写些鲸鱼的诗词
后来他迷上了家用电脑
and then he starts fooling around with a computer.
你猜他现在做什么？ 猜不出
Know what he does now?
他为儿童互动的节目 写电脑软体
He writes software for interactive children's videos.
教孩子们如何平静的解决冲突
They teach kids how to resolve their conflicts peacefully.
天啊！他真聪明 可是这和棒球有什么关系？
God, what an amazing guy.
What's that got to do with baseball?
1962年四月份的喷射杂志中
In the April 1962 issue of Jet Magazine,
there's a story called "This Is Not A Kite."
有一篇他写的故事叫做 “这并不是导管”
It's not his best work,
虽然不是他最好的作品
but the story's hero
有一篇他写的故事叫做 “这并不是导管”
虽然不是他最好的作品
but the story's hero
但在二十六年前 他创造的英雄却叫约翰康斯拉
is named John Kinsella, my father.
就是我父亲      哇！
What do you mean, "Wow"?
你这个“哇”是什么意思
Big wow! What's it got to do with baseball?
那你要我怎么说呢？ 但这和棒球有什么关系？
你这个“哇”是什么意思
Big wow! What's it got to do with baseball?
那你要我怎么说呢？ 但这和棒球有什么关系？
你来开
You drive.
那你要我怎么说呢？ 但这和棒球有什么关系？
你来开
You drive.
最后一次采访他 是在1973年，你猜主题是什么
Okay, the last interview he ever gave was in 1973.
Guess what it's about.
是某种运动团体吗？
Some kind of team sport.
Mann was a baseball fanatic. Listen to this.
他居然是个棒球迷 你听这一段
"My earliest recurring dream was to play at Ebbets Field
“从儿时起，我的梦想就是 参加布鲁克林的道奇队”
他居然是个棒球迷 你听这一段
"My earliest recurring dream was to play at Ebbets Field
“从儿时起，我的梦想就是 参加布鲁克林的道奇队”
“在艾柏特球场 和杰基罗宾逊一起打球”
"with Jackie Robinson and the Brooklyn Dodgers.
“从儿时起，我的梦想就是 参加布鲁克林的道奇队”
“在艾柏特球场 和杰基罗宾逊一起打球”
"with Jackie Robinson and the Brooklyn Dodgers.
“当然，这个梦永远没有实现 后来道奇离开布鲁克林”
"It never happened. The Dodgers left Brooklyn.
“艾柏特球场也被拆了”
"Ebbets Field is gone, but I still dream that dream."
“但是即使到了现在 我仍然常做这个梦”
“艾柏特球场也被拆了”
"Ebbets Field is gone, but I still dream that dream."
“但是即使到了现在 我仍然常做这个梦”
好悲哀哟
That's sad.
“但是即使到了现在 我仍然常做这个梦”
好悲哀哟
That's sad.
他写过他那时代最好的书
The man wrote the best books of his generation.
更是民权和反战运动的拓荒者
He was a pioneer in the civil rights and the antiwar movement.
他曾是新闻周刊的封面人物 他了解各种人，做过各种事
I mean, he made the cover of Newsweek.
He knew everybody. He did everything. He helped shape his time.
他帮忙塑造了他的时代 甚至和披头四合唱团在一起过
The guy hung out with the Beatles.
但是到头来，还是不够 因为他没打成棒球
It wasn't enough. What he missed was baseball.
喔，我的天！      什么事？
Oh, my God! What?
他小时候 有个球棒叫“玫瑰花蕾”
"As a small boy, he had a bat named Rosebud."
让我看      抱歉
Give me that. Sorry.
安妮，自从1958年后 他就一直没到球场看过球赛
The guy hasn't been to a baseball game since 1958.
所以为了抚平他的伤痛 你要带他去看球赛？
So, in order to ease his pain, you're supposed to take him to a ballgame.
没错
Yes.
Ray, this is nuttier than building the baseball field.
这比盖球场还疯狂
No. No, it's not.
不，我同意这很荒谬
It's pretty weird, but building the field was 5, 10% weirder.
但盖球场却比这更怪异
不，我同意这很荒谬
It's pretty weird, but building the field was 5, 10% weirder.
但盖球场却比这更怪异
抱歉老兄 这次我恐怕要反对了
I'm going to have to nip this one in the bud.
但盖球场却比这更怪异
抱歉老兄 这次我恐怕要反对了
I'm going to have to nip this one in the bud.
我们的财务现在正陷入困境
We're having moderate-to-heavy financial difficulties here.
当我们在爱荷华宣布破产时 你怎么可以躲到波士顿去
And you can't take off for Boston while we're going broke in Iowa.
对我们来说这是个全新的领域
This is really new territory for us,
但是我们所接触的 是自然界的神奇力量
but we're dealing with primal forces of nature.
当这种力量叫你做事的时候
The prudent thing is not to quibble over details.
通常只讲大纲不讲细节
Yeah, but why do you have to go? Why can't the voice send somebody else?
为什么要你去做？ 为什么不叫别人去做？
通常只讲大纲不讲细节
Yeah, but why do you have to go? Why can't the voice send somebody else?
为什么要你去做？ 为什么不叫别人去做？
叫莎利麦克莲去嘛，她又不忙
How about Shirley MacLaine? Is she too busy?
为什么要你去做？ 为什么不叫别人去做？
叫莎利麦克莲去嘛，她又不忙
How about Shirley MacLaine? Is she too busy?
这和你有什么关系？ 所以我要去查明呀
What does this have to do with you?
That's what I have to find out.
瑞，我们的贷款快付不出来了
Ray, we are behind on the mortgage. That field ate up all of our savings.
球场把我们的积蓄全吃光 现在连农场怕也保不住
We could lose this farm.
我不住旅馆 就睡在车上，沿路向人乞食
I won't even stay in motels. I'll sleep in the car. I'll beg for food.
No. No! Now, this is too much!
这实在太过份了
我知道你想向世界和自己证明
Now, look. I understand your need to prove to yourself and to the world
你不会步上你父亲的后尘 可以你已经证明了
you are not turning into your father, but you've done it.
你相信奇迹，它也发生了 难道这还不够吗？
You believed in the magic. It happened. Isn't that enough?
安妮，不止如此而已 我知道我像个疯子，可是…
It's more than that. I know this is totally nuts,
but there's another reason I'm supposed to do it.
一定有要我去做的原因
I feel it as strongly as I've felt anything.
我从没有过这么强烈的感觉 一定有原因的
一定有要我去做的原因
I feel it as strongly as I've felt anything.
我从没有过这么强烈的感觉 一定有原因的
There's a reason.
是什么？告诉我是什么原因
What? Just tell me what it is.
我从没有过这么强烈的感觉 一定有原因的
是什么？告诉我是什么原因
What? Just tell me what it is.
我觉得比赛时会有事发生 可是不知道…
Something's going to happen at the game.
There's something at Fenway Park.
但是我必须 和泰伦斯孟到芬威球场
I got to be there with Terence Mann to find it out.
去找出原因来
Is Fenway the one with the big green wall in left field?
芬威球场的左边 是不是有面大绿墙？
去找出原因来
Is Fenway the one with the big green wall in left field?
芬威球场的左边 是不是有面大绿墙？
是的
Yeah.
芬威球场的左边 是不是有面大绿墙？
是的
Yeah.
昨晚我梦到 你和泰伦斯孟在芬威球场
I dreamt last night you were at Fenway with Terence Mann.
我是不是坐在一垒那边？ 对
Was I sitting on the first base side? Yes.
差不多在一半的地方 没错，你在吃热狗
About halfway up on the aisle?
Yeah. Eating a hot dog. Eating a hot dog.
我在吃热狗 我也做了同样的梦
I had the same dream.
我去帮你装行李
I'll help you pack.
嗨，我是瑞康斯拉
Hi, I'm...
Hi, I'm Ray Kinsella.
Hi. No.
Hi.
嗨，我是瑞康斯拉 真高兴我们终于…
Hi, I'm Ray Kinsella. It's a great pleasure to finally get to...
嗨，我是瑞康斯拉 非常崇拜你
Hi, I'm Ray Kinsella. I'm a big fan of yours.
Hi.
泰伦斯孟先生，你好 我要带你去看棒球赛
How do you do, Mr. Mann?
I have to take you to a base...
好吧，笨蛋，把手举起来 到行李箱里去
All right, stupid, put your hands up and get in the trunk.
这倒是好方法
Good. Good.
他就住在这附近 你认识他吗？
He lives right around here. Do you know him?
他是个高个子的黑人 我是他的朋友
He's sort of a tall black man. I'm a friend of his.
既然是朋友 他就该告诉你怎么走
If he was much of a friend, he could give you the directions himself.
你说得不错，谢谢你
That's a good point. Thank you.
走开，我不知道他住在哪里
I don't know where he lives. Get away from me!
我绝不会告诉你的 走开，讨厌鬼
I ain't going to tell you nothing.
Go away! You're a pest!
再过两条街的右手边
Two blocks down, right-hand side.
窗上没鸡的那扇门就是他的
First door that don't have a chicken in the window is his.
没有鸡
No chicken.
这里没鸡
“海达正统家禽、家畜店”
“联合电脑软体”
你是个什么东西？
Who the hell are you?
我的名字是瑞康斯拉
Sir, my name's Ray Kinsella.
你的智商有问题吗？ 泰伦斯孟先生…
We got a learning disability here?
If I could just have one minute, please.
请给我一分钟就好 你听着
Look, I can't tell you the secret of life,
我不知道生命的秘密 也没有你要寻找的答案
and I don't have any answers for you.
我不接受访问 也不再是公众人物
I don't give interviews, and I'm no longer a public figure.
我只想安静的过日子 所以请你滚吧
I just want to be left alone, so piss off.
等一等
Wait! Wait!
我开了1，500哩的路
Look, I've come 1,500 miles to see you
冒着妻离家破的危险来看你
at the risk of losing my home and alienating my wife.
我只要求你给我一分钟
All I'm asking is one minute.
求求你
Please.
那就一分钟
One minute.
我知道你喜欢清净
Okay, I understand your desire for privacy,
如果不是这么重要 我也不敢来打扰你
and I wouldn't dream of intruding if this weren't extremely important.
天呀，我已经不做诉讼了
Oh, God. I don't do causes anymore.
不是诉讼 也不是向你要钱或背书
This isn't a cause.
I don't need money or an endorsement.
这倒挺新鲜的 你曾经写过…
Refreshing.
You once wrote,
“当宇宙的齿轮 转到一个和谐点时”
"There comes a time when all the cosmic tumblers have clicked into place
“天地万物就会开放几秒钟”
"and the universe opens itself up for a few seconds
"to show you what's possible."
“允许你看到未来”
Oh, my God!
老天爷！      怎么啦？
“允许你看到未来”
Oh, my God!
老天爷！      怎么啦？
What?
你来自六零年代吧 对，实际上…
You're from the '60s.
老天爷！      怎么啦？
你来自六零年代吧 对，实际上…
You're from the '60s.
Well, yeah. Actually...
出去！再回到你的六零年代去 喂，等一下
Out! Hey!
Back to the '60s.
在还能回去的时候快回去 这里根本不适合你
No place for you here in the future. Get back while you still can!
你变了，你知道吧
You've changed, you know that?
我是变了，这样如何？
Yes, I suppose I have.
How about this? Peace, love, dope. Now get the hell out of here!
和平、爱、毒品 你给我滚出去！
你现在真惹火我了 好，站在那里别动
You've really pissed me off.
Hold it.
本来我不想这么做的
I was hoping I wouldn't have to do it this way.
那是什么鬼东西？ 枪，你以为是什么？
What the hell is that?
It's a gun.
你的手指头      不，是枪
It's your finger.
No, it's a gun.
是吗？让我看 我才不会让你看我的枪
Let me see it.
I'm not going to show you my gun.
放心，我不会伤害你 只是要你和我出去一下
I'm not going to hurt you. I need you to come with...
你想干什么？
What are you doing?
我会用铁撬打到你走为止
I'll beat you with a crowbar until you go away.
你不能那么做 笑话，这还会有规矩吗？
Wait! You can't do that.
There are rules here? No. There are no rules here.
抱歉没有
你本是个和平主义者
You're a pacifist!
抱歉没有
你本是个和平主义者
You're a pacifist!
该死
Shit.
谢谢你
Thank you. Thank you.
你想绑架我吗？
So what? You kidnapping me? What's the deal here?
到底想干嘛？
I was...
我只是想说服你和我一起出去
I was hoping I could just convince you to come with me.
所以就绑架我？
So you are kidnapping me?
我要带你去看棒球赛
I have to take you to a baseball game.
你要干什么？ 去看今晚红袜对抗天使的比赛
You what?
Tonight's game. Red Sox, A's.
为什么？
Why?
因为会有事发生 现在还不清楚
Something will happen there.
I don't know what, but we'll find out when it does.
到时候我们自然会知道
我叫瑞康斯拉 我父亲的名字是约翰康斯拉
My name's Ray Kinsella.
You used my father's name for a character in one of your stories.
你曾在书中用过他的名字
John Kinsella.
你的精神病医生大概有一箩筐
You're seeing a whole team of psychiatrists, aren't you?
我不怪你这么想 可是我真的没疯
I don't blame you for thinking that, but, no, I'm not.
我可以对天发誓 我真的很正常
I swear to God, I'm the least crazy person I've ever known.
那你为什么绑架我去看球赛
Why are you kidnapping me to a baseball game?
我可以坐… 请坐，要不要咖啡？
May I...
Please.
Want a cup of coffee?
No.
不用了
Want some cookies?
饼干呢？
不用了
Want some cookies?
No.
也不要
I read an interview you gave a long time ago
我看过一篇很久以前你的专访
about how you always dreamed of playing at Ebbets Field
其中提到你的梦想 是在艾柏特球场打球
and how sad you felt when they tore it down.
还有当他们拆除球场时 你有多伤心
I never said that.
我从没说过
还有当他们拆除球场时 你有多伤心
I never said that.
我从没说过
你没有？ 我连想也没想过
You didn't?
I don't even recall thinking that.
那就奇怪了
This is so weird.
This whole...
这…整件事实在太怪异
This whole thing is so weird.
那又何必去做呢？
Then why go through with it?
故事很长
It's a long story.
而且很棒
But it's a really good story.
我会在车上告诉你
I'll tell you on the way.
看来我是摆脱不了你了
I'm not going to get rid of you, am I?
只要你和我去看球赛
Come to this game. I'll never bother you again, not even...
我发誓将来保证不再烦你 连圣诞卡也不会寄给你
只要你和我去看球赛
Come to this game. I'll never bother you again, not even...
我发誓将来保证不再烦你 连圣诞卡也不会寄给你
Not even a Christmas card.
这些年来你都做些什么？
So what do you do with yourself these days?
我享受人生、努力工作
I live, I work.
我学会了做菜
I learned how to cook.
更爱边散步，边观赏落日
I take walks and watch sunsets.
你难道不怀念过去的风光？
Don't you miss being involved?
我曾是东岸混乱的批发商
I was the East Coast distributor of involved.
随时在制造混乱
I ate it and drank it and breathed it.
后来他们杀了马丁和巴比
Then they killed Martin and Bobby,
而狡猾的尼克森又两度当选
they elected Tricky Dick twice,
你以为我会因 往日的风光不再而痛不欲生？
and now people like you think
I must be miserable because I'm not involved anymore.
让我告诉你
I've got news for you.
以前的日子才悲惨
I spent all my misery years ago.
如今我不必为别人去努力
I have no more pain left for any of you.
只为自己而忙
I gave at the office.
So what do you want?
好，你想要什么？
I want them to stop looking to me for answers,
我要他们 别叫我去替他们寻找答案
好，你想要什么？
I want them to stop looking to me for answers,
我要他们 别叫我去替他们寻找答案
或要求我再开始演讲、写作 做他们的领导人
begging me to speak again, write again, be a leader.
我要他们 别叫我去替他们寻找答案
或要求我再开始演讲、写作 做他们的领导人
begging me to speak again, write again, be a leader.
我要他们开始为自己思考
I want them to start thinking for themselves.
我要有自己的私生活
I want my privacy.
不，我是问你想要什么？
No, I meant what do you want?
热狗和啤酒
Dog and a beer.
来两份
Two.
一共十块钱
10 bucks.
我了解你的想法
Okay, I understand.
你有权力拥有自己的私生活
You should be entitled to as much privacy as you want,
可是为什么停止写作？
but why stop writing?
十七年来我没出过一本书
I haven't published a word in 17 years,
却仍要忍受你这种疯子
and still I have to endure lunatics like you.
你想若我突然出书 会发生什么情况？
What do you think would happen if I suddenly came out with a new book?
他们会把我榨干的
They'd bleed me dry.
到远方去
Go the distance.
“艾契月光葛汉，明尼苏达 奇斯何姆，纽约巨人队”
“终生资料 一场比赛——零打击”
怎么了？
What's the matter?
你没看到？      看到什么？
You didn't see that?
See what?
对不起 我想你不必再待下去了
I'm sorry. I guess you didn't have to be here.
什么？
What?
我们随时可以离开
Whenever you want to go, we can go.
好，那就走吧
Fine. Let's go.
你到底在瞒着我什么？
What is it you're not telling me?
我已经花去你太多时间
I've already taken up too much of your time.
但愿我有你的激情
I wish I had your passion, Ray.
虽然被误导，但仍是激情
Misdirected though it might be, it is still a passion.
我曾经也像你一样，可是…
I used to feel that way about things, but...
你又收到讯息了吗？
You got another message, didn't you?
你一定认为我疯了
You'll think I'm crazy.
我早就这么想了 是什么讯息？
I already think you're crazy.
What did it say?
它说“够了，别再打扰他”
It said, "The man's done enough. Leave him alone."
月光葛汉
"Moonlight" Graham.
你看到了      看到什么？
You saw it.
Saw what?
你看到讯息了 1922年纽约巨人队
You saw it. New York Giants, 1922.
他只参加一场比赛 但没有击球，你看到了
He played one game. He never got to bat.
我看到什么啦？ 明尼苏达州的奇斯何姆
What did I see? Chisholm, Minnesota.
我们是唯一看到它的人
We were the only ones who saw it. Did you hear the voice, too?
你有没有听到声音？
It's what told me to find you. Did you hear it?
你尽管承认 就是它让我来找你的
你有没有听到声音？
It's what told me to find you. Did you hear it?
你听到了吗？
你有没有听到声音？
It's what told me to find you. Did you hear it?
你听到了吗？
“到远方去”
"Go the distance"?
对！你知道是什么意思吗？
Yes. Do you know what it means?
知道      什么意思？
Yes.
What?
它叫我们到明尼苏达州 去找月光葛汉
It means we're going to Minnesota to find "Moonlight" Graham.
我们？你说我们吗？
We're going... We?
我一定也疯了
I must be out of my mind.
找到他后怎么办？
What do we do when we find him?
我怎么会晓得
How the hell am I supposed to know?
没错，一点也没错
That's right. You're right. You're right.
太不可思议了 真不相信我也会这么疯
This is so bitching.
I don't believe I'm doing this.
嘿，安妮 我现在和泰伦斯孟在一起
Hey, Annie, guess what? I'm with Terence Mann.
天呀，你绑架他了
Oh, my God. You kidnapped him.
No, I didn't. He wanted to.
没有，他是自愿的
Sorry, but I'm going to be a few days longer.
对不起，我得再多待几天
没有，他是自愿的
Sorry, but I'm going to be a few days longer.
对不起，我得再多待几天
我们要去明尼苏达州 真的吗？
- We're going to Minnesota. - I don't believe this.
对不起，我得再多待几天
我们要去明尼苏达州 真的吗？
- We're going to Minnesota. - I don't believe this.
为什么去明尼苏达呢？ 为了一个老球员
What's in Minnesota?
An old ballplayer. I'll explain when I get home.
等回家后再解释
How are things with you?
你那边都好吧？
Fine.
很好      那就好
Great. Look, Ann, I got to go, okay?
我得挂电话了
很好      那就好
Great. Look, Ann, I got to go, okay?
我得挂电话了
替我抱抱凯伦，还有我爱你
Give Karin a hug for me,
我得挂电话了
替我抱抱凯伦，还有我爱你
Give Karin a hug for me,
and I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
将来你一定要解释清楚好吗？
Hey, someday explain all this to me, okay?
I'll try.
我会尽量的，再见
Bye-bye.
再见
Bye.
你为什么不告诉他？
Why didn't you tell him?
Annie, you got no choice in the matter.
安妮，你现在毫无选择
“奇斯何姆百年纪念日”
一堆姓葛汉的人
Half a dozen Grahams.
就是没有艾契或月光
No Archibald. No "Moonlight."
跟我来
Follow me.
“论坛报”
哈啰
Hello.
我们想请你帮个忙
Excuse me. Maybe you can help us.
我们在找前棒球员艾契葛汉
We're looking for an ex-baseball player named Archibald Graham.
喔，你是指葛汉医生
You mean Doc Graham.
不，他的绰号是月光
No. I think his nickname was "Moonlight."
那就是葛汉医生
Well, that's Dr. Graham.
葛汉医生？
Dr. Graham?
他的棒球生涯一直没多大发展 所以又回学校念书
His baseball career never amounted to much.
He went back to school.
他父亲是个医生 我们怎么才能找到他
His father was a doctor.
Do you know where we can find him?
放心，我们不是税务局的人
It's nothing bad. We're not from the IRS.
葛汉医生已经死了
Doc Graham is dead.
他死于1972年
He died in 1972.
“曾经有段时间人们无法负担”
"And there were times when children could not afford
“孩子们的眼镜、牛奶或衣服”
"eyeglasses or milk or clothing.
“然而他们却从不缺乏这些”
"Yet, no child was ever denied these essentials
“全是因为葛汉医生的原故”
"because, in the background, there was always Dr. Graham.
“他不为虚名”
"Without any fanfare or publicity,
“只是默默的把眼镜、牛奶 或是球赛的票”
"the glasses or the milk or the ticket to the ballgame
“悄悄的放到孩子们的衣袋里”
"found their way into the child's pocket."
You wrote that.
是你写的
The day he died.
就在他死的那一天 我能看吗？
Can I see that?
你是个好作家
You're a good writer.
你也一样
So are you.
到底缺了什么？
Something's missing.
听起来他是个大好人
Well, he sounds like he was a wonderful man.
在北部有一堆葛汉医生
Half the towns in North America have a Doc Graham.
为什么在死后十六年
What makes this one so special we travel across the country to find him
居然让我们 横越半个大陆来找他
16 years after he died?
他到底有什么特殊？
居然让我们 横越半个大陆来找他
16 years after he died?
他到底有什么特殊？
一定有别的原因
There's got to be more.
还有什么？
What else?
他永远都穿着大衣
He always wore an overcoat,
一头白发，手里拿着雨伞
he had white hair,
and he always carried an umbrella.
为什么要拿雨伞？ 我想是一种习惯
What was the umbrella for?
It got to be a habit, something to hang on to.
让手上握着点东西
He said he used it to beat away his lady admirers.
如果问他，他会说 是为了赶走那些女性爱慕者
让手上握着点东西
He said he used it to beat away his lady admirers.
如果问他，他会说 是为了赶走那些女性爱慕者
那他的太太呢？
Tell me about his wife.
如果问他，他会说 是为了赶走那些女性爱慕者
那他的太太呢？
Tell me about his wife.
爱丽莎
Alicia.
在葛汉医生过逝后
She moved to South Carolina after Doc passed.
她搬到南卡罗来纳州
在葛汉医生过逝后
She moved to South Carolina after Doc passed.
她搬到南卡罗来纳州
几年后也去逝了
She passed a couple years later.
她搬到南卡罗来纳州
几年后也去逝了
She passed a couple years later.
她喜欢戴蓝帽子
She always wore blue.
城里的店主们
The shopkeepers in town would stock blue hats
会买许多蓝帽子
because they knew if Doc walked by, he'd buy one.
因为他们知道如果医生看到了
会买许多蓝帽子
because they knew if Doc walked by, he'd buy one.
一定会买
会买许多蓝帽子
because they knew if Doc walked by, he'd buy one.
一定会买
当他们打扫他诊所时
When they cleaned out his office,
找到一堆全新的蓝帽子
they found boxes of blue hats
还没来得及送给她前就死了
that he never got around to give her.
这事你一定不知道
I'll bet you didn't know that.
是不知道
No, I didn't.
他不滥交、不酗酒
No screwing, no drinking, no opium, no midnight abortions,
不抽大麻、不替人堕胎
他不滥交、不酗酒
No screwing, no drinking, no opium, no midnight abortions,
不抽大麻、不替人堕胎
没有私生子
no illegitimate children,
不抽大麻、不替人堕胎
没有私生子
no illegitimate children,
也没有财务危机
no shady finances.
你好像很失望
You sound disappointed.
赤脚乔他有问题 所以才需要你
Shoeless Joe had a problem. That's why he needed you.
可是他根本不需要我们
This guy doesn't need us.
泰伦斯
Terence.
你知道你失踪了吗？
Do you know you're missing?
啊！我的天
Oh, God.
“他那住在巴尔的摩的父亲”
"His father, who lives in Baltimore,
“在打了数通无人接的电话后 已向警方报案”
"notified police after receiving no answer to repeated telephone calls."
糟糕，我最好打电话给他
Shoot.
I better call him.
要不要我…
You want me to...
谢谢你
Thanks.
我出去散步，等会儿回来
I'm taking a walk. Be back in a while.
我该怎么对他说？
What do I tell him?
“艾咪咖啡店”
“四年后重选总统”
“教父，今年排行前十名”
“今年”
"This year's"?
葛汉医生？
Dr. Graham?
我是从爱荷华来的瑞康斯拉
My name's Ray Kinsella. I'm from Iowa.
你是月光葛汉吗？
Are you "Moonlight" Graham?
已经五十年没人这么叫我了
No one's called me "Moonlight" Graham in 50 years.
我是从很远的地方来看你
Well, I've come a very long way to see you.
通常我睡得像小孩一样 可是今晚却睡不着
I couldn't sleep tonight. Usually I sleep like a baby.
所以告诉爱丽莎我要出来散步
I told Alicia I was taking a walk.
我能和你一起散步吗？ 我很想和你聊聊
Do you mind if I join you?
I'd like to talk to you.
那一起到我诊所去
Let's walk over to my office.
你想和我聊什么？
What do you want to talk to me about?
当你参加巨人队时 只打了一局
When you got to the majors, you played only one inning of one game.
怎么会那样？
What happened that inning?
那是季赛的最后一天
It was the last day of the season,
第八局的后半局 我们远远超过对方
bottom of the eighth, we were way ahead.
我参加巨人队大约三个礼拜 但没什么刺激的比赛
In three weeks, I hadn't seen any action.
突然约翰麦格罗指着我的方向
Suddenly old John McGraw points a bony finger in my direction
说“右野”
and he says, "Right field."
我像从弹簧上弹起来一样
I jumped up like I was sitting on a spring,
抓起手套立刻跑向右野
grabbed my glove, and ran out on the field.
你有任何表现吗？
Did you get to make a play?
可惜球一直没打到外野来
They never hit the ball out of the infield.
比赛结束，季赛也完了
The game ended. The season was over.
我知道他们不会要我
I knew they'd send me back down.
而我不愿意再花一年的时间 做乙等球队的队员
I couldn't bear the thought of another year in the minors.
所以决定放弃棒球
So I decided to hang them up.
请坐
Go on. Sit down.
谢谢你
Thank you.
那你有什么感觉？
So what was that like?
就差这么一点，梦想就能实现
It was like coming this close to your dreams,
但它却像陌生人般的 和你擦身而过
then watch them brush past you, like a stranger in a crowd.
当初并没有这种感觉
Then, you don't think about it.
我们往往不能认清 一生中的关键时刻
We just don't recognize life's most significant moments
while they're happening.
那时我常说“以后还有机会”
Back then I thought, "Well, there'll be other days."
却没料到那是唯一的机会
I didn't realize that that was the only day.
And now, I want to ask you a question.
瑞，我现在想问你个问题
是什么动机让你在五十年后
What's so interesting about half an inning that you'd come from Iowa
瑞，我现在想问你个问题
是什么动机让你在五十年后
What's so interesting about half an inning that you'd come from Iowa
大老远的从爱荷华到这里来
to talk to me about it 50 years after it happened?
和我谈那半局的比赛呢？
大老远的从爱荷华到这里来
to talk to me about it 50 years after it happened?
和我谈那半局的比赛呢？
老实说，到现在我才知道原因 我想该这么问你
I didn't really know till just now,
but I think it's to ask you if you could do anything you wanted,
如果你能做任何你想做的事
如果你能让梦想成真
if you could have a wish...
如果你能做任何你想做的事
如果你能让梦想成真
if you could have a wish...
而你就是 能使我梦想成真的人？
And you're the kind of a man who could grant me that wish?
只是问问，我不能确定
I don't know. I'm just asking.
你是知道的…
Well, you know,
我没有在职业棒球赛中击过球
I never got to bat in the major leagues.
所以希望有一天能有机会
I'd have liked to have had that chance, just once,
用眼睛盯着那一流的投手
to stare down a big-league pitcher.
盯着他直到他挥臂准备投球 然后一眨眼
Then just as he goes into his windup, wink.
让他以为我看出什么破绽
Make him think you know something he doesn't.
我的梦想就是 眯着眼看着天空
That's what I wish for.
The chance to squint at a sky so blue it hurts your eyes to look at it,
它蓝得那么刺眼
to feel the tingle in your arms as you connect with the ball,
在击球时臂膀刺痛的感觉
它蓝得那么刺眼
to feel the tingle in your arms as you connect with the ball,
在击球时臂膀刺痛的感觉
跑垒时，为了盗垒
run bases, stretching a double into a triple and flop face first into third,
在击球时臂膀刺痛的感觉
跑垒时，为了盗垒
run bases, stretching a double into a triple and flop face first into third,
脸先着地的扑向垒包
wrap your arms around the bag.
伸长手臂去触摸垒包
That's my wish. That's my wish.
那是我的梦想 瑞，那就是我的梦想
伸长手臂去触摸垒包
That's my wish. That's my wish.
那是我的梦想 瑞，那就是我的梦想
在这月光之下 真有那神奇的力量
Is there enough magic out there in the moonlight
能让我的梦想成真吗？
to make this dream come true?
如果我说能，你信吗？
What would you say if I said yes?
我还真会相信你
I think I'd actually believe you.
那么有一个地方 能让你的梦想成真
There's a place where things like that happen.
如果你愿意，我可以带你去
If you want to go, I can take you.
对我来说 这里是全世界最特殊的地方
This is my most special place in all the world.
它对我的影响非常大
Once a place touches you like this, the wind never blows so cold again.
让我感觉不到风的冰冷
它对我的影响非常大
Once a place touches you like this, the wind never blows so cold again.
让我感觉不到风的冰冷
它就像我的小孩一样
You feel for it, like it was your child.
我不能离开奇斯何姆
I can't leave Chisholm.
我了解
I understand. I do.
真的了解
可是我仍旧认为 你应该和我们一起去
But I really think you're supposed to come with us.
No.
可是你的梦想呢？
But your wish?
就继续做梦吧！
It'll have to stay a wish.
我生在这儿、长在这儿
I was born here, I lived here, I'll die here, but no regrets.
也要死在这儿，绝不后悔
我生在这儿、长在这儿
I was born here, I lived here, I'll die here, but no regrets.
也要死在这儿，绝不后悔
在五十年前 有五分钟你的梦想几乎实现
Fifty years ago, for 5 minutes you came this close.
It would kill some men
有人会为错过举手可得的机会 而顿足捶胸
to get that close to their dream and not touch it.
甚至把它当成一场悲剧
God. They'd consider it a tragedy.
孩子，反过来看 如果做医生是我那没实现的梦
If I'd only gotten to be a doctor for five minutes,
now that would have been a tragedy.
我认为那才是真正的悲剧
我得回家了
I better be getting home. Alicia will think I got a girlfriend.
否则爱丽莎以为我有女朋友了
我得回家了
I better be getting home. Alicia will think I got a girlfriend.
否则爱丽莎以为我有女朋友了
然后他笑了
And he smiled.
后来我想…
And then I figured, maybe we're not supposed to take him with us.
也许我们根本不该带他走
后来我想…
And then I figured, maybe we're not supposed to take him with us.
也许我们根本不该带他走
我真的不懂
I don't know.
也许我们根本不该带他走
我真的不懂
I don't know.
现在好啦 为什么要我们来这里呢
I don't know why in the hell we were supposed to come here.
也许是来探讨 一局比赛能否改变世界
Maybe it's to find out if one inning can change the world.
能吗？ 的确曾改变过一些人
Think it did?
Did for these people.
如果他击过球 或许就会留在棒球队里
If he'd gotten a hit, he might have stayed in baseball.
我也搞不清
I don't know.
你太太打过电话来
Your wife called. She wants you to call her tonight.
她要你今晚打电话回去
你太太打过电话来
Your wife called. She wants you to call her tonight.
她要你今晚打电话回去
是瑞吗？
Ray?
我很好，真高兴是你
I'm fine. I'm just so glad it's you.
我和银行谈过
Listen, I talked to the bank,
并且问他们 可不可以迟付几个月
and I asked them if we could miss a payment or two,
他们说已经把农场的借据
and they told me that they had just sold the note on the farm
卖给马克和他的合伙人
to Mark and his partners.
所以他们是债权人了
Right. So they own the paper now.
他说若不卖给他们 农场就会被拍卖
He says if we don't sell to them, they're going to foreclose.
我们现在一点钱也没有
Ray, we don't have the money.
好，我计划…
Look, I've got to take Mr. Mann back to Boston first.
先送泰伦斯孟回波士顿
Okay? So, it's...
所以要…
No.
不
Wait a second.
你等一下
I'm going to Iowa with you.
我和你一起回爱荷华
你等一下
I'm going to Iowa with you.
我和你一起回爱荷华
我们马上回家
We're coming home.
我现在绝不能放弃
Hell, I can't quit now. I got to see this ballpark.
一定要看看这个球场
Not everyone can see it. You might not.
并不是人人都能看到 也许你就看不到
一定要看看这个球场
Not everyone can see it. You might not.
并不是人人都能看到 也许你就看不到
总得去试试
Give it a try.
并不是人人都能看到 也许你就看不到
总得去试试
Give it a try.
从现在起我得要多积阴德
I need all the karma I can get right now.
谢谢，你是第一辆车
Thanks. You're the first car by.
你到哪里去？ 你们要去哪里呢？
How far you going?
爱荷华
Iowa.
那我能不能和你们走一段
If it's okay, I'll just ride along a while. I play baseball.
我是打棒球的
那我能不能和你们走一段
If it's okay, I'll just ride along a while. I play baseball.
我是打棒球的
上车吧      谢谢
Hop in. All right.
我想找个地方打球 听说在中西部很多城市
I'm looking for a place to play.
I heard that all through the Midwest, they have towns with teams.
都有自己的球队
In some places, they'll find you a day job
有些球队 甚至会替你找份白天的工作
都有自己的球队
In some places, they'll find you a day job
有些球队 甚至会替你找份白天的工作
好让你在晚上或周末打球
so you can play ball nights and weekends.
有些球队 甚至会替你找份白天的工作
好让你在晚上或周末打球
so you can play ball nights and weekends.
你运气真好 我们就是去那种地方
It's your lucky day. We're going someplace kind of like that.
太棒了！
All right.
我是瑞康斯拉 这位是泰伦斯孟
I'm Ray Kinsella. This is Terence Mann.
你们好
Hi.
我叫艾契葛汉
I'm Archie Graham.
奇怪他所形容的那种 参加他们的球队
It's funny the way he described towns finding you a job
就替你找工作的那件事
so you could play on their team.
已经停止很久了
They haven't done that for years.
我父亲曾经参加过 但那是贰零年代的事
Dad did that for a while, but that was in the '20s.
你父亲后来怎么了？
What happened to your father?
他棒球生涯一直没有成就 只好将希望寄托在儿子身上
He never made it as a ballplayer. He wanted his son to make it for him.
在我十岁时，打棒球就像
By 10, playing baseball got to be like eating vegetables or taking out garbage.
吃蔬菜、倒垃圾那么平常
在我十岁时，打棒球就像
By 10, playing baseball got to be like eating vegetables or taking out garbage.
吃蔬菜、倒垃圾那么平常
可是到了十四岁我开始拒绝
When I was 14, I started to refuse.
吃蔬菜、倒垃圾那么平常
可是到了十四岁我开始拒绝
When I was 14, I started to refuse.
你能相信吗？
Can you believe that?
美国小男孩 居然不愿意和父亲玩接球
American boy refusing to have a catch with his father?
为什么在十四岁？
Why 14?
因为我刚看完泰伦斯孟 那本“摇篮般的小船”
That's when I read The Boat Rocker by Terence Mann.
哟，天呀 从此不再和他玩接球
Oh, God.
I never played catch with him again.
我怎么会那么倒楣 你不要和父亲玩球
That's the crap people always lay on me.
又不是我的错
It's not my fault you wouldn't play catch with him.
我知道
I know.
后来，到了十七岁
Anyway, when I was 17,
我把行李一装 说了些狠话就走了
I packed my things, said something awful, and left.
过了一段时间 想回家却不知该怎么做
After a while, I wanted to come home, but I didn't know how.
最后只去参加他的葬礼
Made it back for the funeral, though.
你说了什么狠话？
What was the awful thing you said?
对你的父亲？
To your father?
我说我无法尊敬 一个把罪犯视为英雄的人
I said I could never respect a man whose hero was a criminal.
他的英雄是谁？
Who was his hero?
赤脚乔杰克森
Shoeless Joe Jackson.
你应该知道他并不是罪犯
You knew he wasn't a criminal.
为什么你要那么说？
Then why did you say it?
我才十七岁呀
I was 17.
在我能收回这句话之前 他就去逝了
The son of a bitch died before I could take it back.
在我能告诉他…
Before I could tell him,
你知道的
you know.
他从没见过我太太
He never met my wife.
也没见过他的孙女
He never saw his granddaughter.
你是为了赎罪
This is your penance.
我知道
I know.
我不能让父亲复活
I can't bring my father back.
所以至少让他的英雄回来
So the least you can do is bring back his hero.
这…
Well...
大家来这里的目的都已明白
Now I know what everybody's purpose here is,
除了我之外
except mine.
Hey.
爹地！      凯伦，给爹地抱抱
Daddy!
Karin, come here.
嗨！
Hi!
We missed you.
我们很想念你，你还好吧？
Are you, okay?
好，这位是泰伦斯孟
Yeah. This is Terence Mann.
请叫我泰瑞
Terry.
欢迎你来   谢谢你
Welcome.
嗨，泰瑞
Hi, Terry.
这个年轻人是艾契葛汉
And this young fella is... This is Archie Graham.
嗨
Archie.
他是来和球队练球的
He's come to practice with the team.
He'll be able to do a lot more than that.
现在可不止练球而已了 你这是什么意思？
What does that mean?
好啦，快来打球吧
What do you say? What do you say?
你怎么说？
Hey, Ray. Welcome back.
嗨，瑞
你怎么说？
Hey, Ray. Welcome back.
你终于回来了
Thanks, Joe.
谢谢你，乔 我的天！
Oh, my God.
怎么了？ 那是赤脚乔杰克森
What?
That's Shoeless Joe Jackson.
Of course it is.
当然是他，你居然不相信我
You didn't believe me?
我本来相信，可是…
I thought I did, but...
噢，天呐！
Oh, my God.
嗨，安妮      嗨，乔
Hi, Annie. Hi, Joe.
很高兴见到你      我也是
Good to see you.
泰瑞，这位是赤脚乔杰克森
Terry, I'd like you to meet Shoeless Joe Jackson.
乔，这位是泰伦斯孟
Joe, Terry Mann.
真是我天大的荣幸 不，是我的荣幸
It's a pleasure meeting you.
The pleasure's mine.
瑞，希望你不介意 我们练球练烦了
We got tired of just having practices,
所以把另一队叫来 好能来场真正的比赛
so we brought another team out so we'd have some real games.
不介意，他们从哪来的？
I don't mind.
Where'd they come from?
我们又从哪来呢？
Where did we come from?
好多人争着要来这里打球
So many wanted to play here. We had to beat them off with a stick.
我们得用棍子打散他们
Hey, that's Smokey Joe Wood
哇，那是红袜队的史莫基
and Mel Ott
全垒王欧特和红雀队的哈吉斯
and Gil Hodges.
泰柯布也想来
Ty Cobb wanted to play.
可惜我们当时都不喜欢他
Nobody could stand him when we were alive.
所以就叫他滚到一边去
We told him to stick it.
Hey, are you Graham?
你是葛汉？      是的
Yes, sir.
为什么站在那边 你不是来打球的吗？
Why are you on the sidelines? Came to play ball, didn't you?
是的
Yes, sir.
那去暖身吧
All right. Well, go warm up.
是的
Yes, sir.
这些新手
Rookies.
真难以置信
Unbelievable.
你的形容还不够贴切
It's more than that.
是完美
It's perfect.
- Ho! - Safe!
安全上垒
葛汉加油，来支安打
Go, Graham! Go, kid!
加油，葛汉
Come on, Archie!
和他们一比他就像个小婴孩
He looks like a baby next to those guys.
他是个小孩
He is.
打个安打
Let's get a hit.
快点呀
Let's go.
小心
Watch it, boy!
喂，太过份啦
Say hey!
别被他吓到，不要气馁
Don't let him shake you up. Hang in there!
你为什么要往他身上招呼
Knuckles, what did you throw at the kid for?
他对我眨眼   孩子，别眨眼
He winked at me.
Don't wink, kid.
Good thing for you he didn't throw the fastball.
好在他没投快速球
那就让我见识一下快速球
Let's see that fastball.
快点
Let's go. Come on.
耶！      好球
- Yeah! - Ball.
喂，裁判，别欺人太甚
Hey, ump! Come on. Give us a break!
裁判
Hey, ump.
给个警告嘛！      好呀
How about a warning? Sure.
小心被球打死
Watch out you don't get killed.
暂停
Time!
好，前面两球高而且直
Those first two were high and tight.
你想下面一球会如何？
What will the next one be?
我想…
Well, either low and away or in my ear.
不是低而外弯就是朝我耳朵来
我想…
Well, either low and away or in my ear.
不是低而外弯就是朝我耳朵来
他绝不想满垒，所以小心低球
He won't want to load the bases. So look for low and away.
不是低而外弯就是朝我耳朵来
他绝不想满垒，所以小心低球
He won't want to load the bases. So look for low and away.
好
All right.
但是也要注意你的耳朵
But watch out for in your ear.
葛汉加油      继续打球了
- Come on, Archie! - Let's go, kid!
你一定打得到 葛汉，要有信心
Batter, batter, batter, batter!
Come on, Arch. It just takes one.
这次一定行
Never hit it, kid.
你永远打不到
这次一定行
Never hit it, kid.
你永远打不到
让咱们来个满垒
耶！
Yeah. Yeah.
让咱们来个满垒
耶！
Yeah. Yeah.
够远了      回本垒吧
That's deep enough.
快！快回本垒
Go! Go!
Go home!
安全上垒      他妈…
Safe!
Son of a...
葛汉，打得好
Way to go, Arch! Way to go!
葛汉，好样子
Attaboy, Arch!
为葛汉来个波浪欢呼 好本领
This is the wave!
- Way to go, man! - Yeah, Archie.
耶，葛汉   你真行
All right.
我们就需要这一棒 记你一大功
That's what we needed.
Way to go.
Yeah. Way to go.
这是什么？
What is this?
这个混蛋在搞什么？ 嗨！
What is this jerk doing?
Hi!
Shit!
要命！      让我来揍他
Wreck him.
Let me at him!
马克，你打断比赛了
You're interrupting the game, Mark.
瑞，你最好别再做梦
Ray, it's time to put away your little fantasies
and come down to Earth.
不是梦，是真的
It's not a fantasy. They're real.
你说谁是真的？
Who is real?
赤脚乔和所有的白袜队
Shoeless Joe Jackson, the White Sox, all of them.
你是说…
You mean?
他看不到
He can't see any of them.
这又是谁，猫王吗？
Well, who is this, Elvis?
瑞
Ray.
告诉你这位是泰伦斯孟
As a matter of fact, it's Terence Mann.
又在胡说了，你好 我是复活节兔子
How do you do? I'm the Easter bunny.
瑞，我们要快把事情解决
Let's settle this thing now. You have no money.
你没有钱      我绝不卖我的家
Look. I'm not selling. You have no money!
你没钱，却有一堆帐单等着付
You have a stack of bills! Come fall, you got no crop to sell.
到了秋天又没有庄稼能卖钱
I have a deal that allows you to stay on the land.
不过我替你想出办法来 让你能继续住下去
到了秋天又没有庄稼能卖钱
I have a deal that allows you to stay on the land.
不过我替你想出办法来 让你能继续住下去
爹地，我们不用卖农场
We don't have to sell the farm.
不过我替你想出办法来 让你能继续住下去
爹地，我们不用卖农场
We don't have to sell the farm.
把农场卖给我们 房子我们不碰
You'll live in the house rent-free.
你可以免费住在那里 那棒球场怎么办？
What about the team?
你知道这块土地值多少钱吗？
Do you realize how much this land is worth?
知道
Yeah. Yeah.
一亩2，200美金
2,200 bucks an acre.
We can't keep a useless baseball diamond in rich farmland.
那你应该知道 在沃田当中不可能保有棒球场
你听好，我们不卖
Read my lips. We're staying, all right? We're staying.
那你应该知道 在沃田当中不可能保有棒球场
你听好，我们不卖
Read my lips. We're staying, all right? We're staying.
可是你就要破产了
Ray, you're bankrupt!
因为我爱我妹妹 所以才让你保有房子
I'm offering you a way to keep your home because I love my sister.
我的合伙人才不管 他已经准备来拍卖了
My partners don't care and are ready to foreclose.
爹地，我们不必卖农场
Daddy, we don't have to sell the farm.
凯伦，别闹
Karin, please!
Just wait!
等等，让她说
Wait!
人们会来的
People will come.
宝贝，什么人？
What people, sweetheart?
全世界的人
From all over.
当他们要渡假时
They'll just decide to take a vacation, see?
就会来到爱荷华市
And they'll come to Iowa City.
可是那里很无聊 就会开车来这里付我们钱
They'll think it's really boring. So they'll want to pay us.
就像买门票一样
Like buying a ticket.
你不可能认真吧？
You're not seriously listening to this, are you?
我是认真的
Yes.
那你说…
Wait a minute.
人们为什么愿意付钱来这里？
Why would anybody pay money to come here?
看比赛呀
To watch the games.
就像又回到很久很久以前
It will be just like when they were little kids a long time ago.
他们还是小孩的时候
They'll watch the game and remember what it was like.
看着比赛回忆以前的事
他们还是小孩的时候
They'll watch the game and remember what it was like.
看着比赛回忆以前的事
她到底在说什么？
What the hell is she talking about?
看着比赛回忆以前的事
她到底在说什么？
What the hell is she talking about?
人们会来的
People will come.
All right. This is fascinating,
好啦，已经够怪异了
but you don't have the money to bring the mortgage up to date.
问题是你没法准时付贷款
You're still going to have to sell.
到头来仍要卖掉农场
问题是你没法准时付贷款
You're still going to have to sell.
到头来仍要卖掉农场
瑞，你没有选择的余地
I'm sorry, Ray.
到头来仍要卖掉农场
瑞，你没有选择的余地
I'm sorry, Ray.
We got no choice.
瑞，人们会来的
Ray.
People will come, Ray.
他们莫名其妙的来到爱荷华
They'll come to Iowa for reasons they can't even fathom.
莫名其妙的 把车停在你的车道上
They'll turn up your driveway, not knowing for sure why they're doing it.
像天真孩子般的来到你的门口
They'll arrive at your door
as innocent as children, longing for the past.
渴望去寻觅他们的过去
"Of course, we won't mind if you look around," you'll say.
你会说 “欢迎你们到处看看”
渴望去寻觅他们的过去
"Of course, we won't mind if you look around," you'll say.
你会说 “欢迎你们到处看看”
“一个人只要二十元”
"It's only $20 per person."
你会说 “欢迎你们到处看看”
“一个人只要二十元”
"It's only $20 per person."
他们毫不犹豫的把钱交出来
They'll pass over the money without even thinking about it.
因为他们愿意 用钱买回那寻觅已久的宁静
For it is money they have and peace they lack.
瑞，你签字吧
Just sign the papers.
然后在一个晴朗的午后
Then they'll walk out to the bleachers
他们会卷起袖子
and sit in their shirt sleeves on a perfect afternoon.
来到垒边的看台上
They'll find they have reserved seats
在那里会找到 特地为他们预留的座位
somewhere along one of the baselines,
那正是他们小时候
where they sat when they were children
为英雄们欢呼时所坐过的位子
and cheered their heroes,
他们看着比赛
and they'll watch the game,
就像仙棒一挥 又重回到往日的时光
and it will be as if they dipped themselves in magic waters.
回忆是那么的浓
The memories will be so thick,
化不开也拂不去
they'll have to brush them away from their faces.
Ray, when the bank opens in the morning, they'll foreclose.
瑞，明早银行一开门 就会拍卖这个农场
瑞，人们会来的
People will come, Ray.
瑞，明早银行一开门 就会拍卖这个农场
瑞，人们会来的
People will come, Ray.
你已经破产了 如果不卖，连房子也保不住
You're broke, Ray. You sell now, or you lose everything.
多年来唯一不变的
The one constant through all the years, Ray, has been baseball.
就是棒球
America has rolled by like an army of steamrollers.
美国的历史、文化 像被蒸汽压路机般辗了又辗
就是棒球
America has rolled by like an army of steamrollers.
美国的历史、文化 像被蒸汽压路机般辗了又辗
更像黑板上的字
It's been erased like a blackboard, rebuilt, and erased again.
美国的历史、文化 像被蒸汽压路机般辗了又辗
更像黑板上的字
It's been erased like a blackboard, rebuilt, and erased again.
擦了写、写了擦
更像黑板上的字
It's been erased like a blackboard, rebuilt, and erased again.
擦了写、写了擦
但是棒球…
But baseball has marked the time.
却留下了不朽的脚印
但是棒球…
But baseball has marked the time.
却留下了不朽的脚印
这个球场、这个比赛
This field, this game.
却留下了不朽的脚印
这个球场、这个比赛
This field, this game.
全是我们的过去
It's a part of our past, Ray.
它唤起了过去的好时光
It reminds us of all that once was good,
和对将来的憧憬
and it could be again.
People will come, Ray.
人们会来
People will most definitely come.
一定会来的
人们会来
People will most definitely come.
一定会来的
瑞，你会失去一切
Ray, you will lose everything.
一定会来的
瑞，你会失去一切
Ray, you will lose everything.
会被赶出去
You will be evicted.
签吧
Come on, Ray.
我不签      你疯了
I'm not signing.
You're crazy. Absolutely nuts!
你是彻底的疯了
I can't do it, pal.
老兄，我不能签
I mean, you build a baseball field
你在这鸟不拉屎的地方 盖了座球场
in the middle of nowhere, and you stare at nothing.
然后盯着空球场猛看
It's not nothing. Your daughter's turned into a space case.
它不是空的
然后盯着空球场猛看
It's not nothing. Your daughter's turned into a space case.
你把女儿也弄得精神恍惚
Get your hands off her!
放开她！      我只是想帮你
你把女儿也弄得精神恍惚
Get your hands off her!
放开她！      我只是想帮你
Karin?
凯伦！
她还好吗？      我不知道
Is she all right? Is she breathing?
有呼吸吗？      我去开车
Should I get the car?
我去叫救护车
I'm going to call Emergency.
安妮，等等
Annie, wait.
你说什么？
What?
你等一下
Just wait.
小家伙怎么了？   她摔下来
What have we got here?
She fell.
她噎住了，把她扶起来
This child's choking to death. Get her up.
扶稳
Hold her steady now.
热狗卡在喉咙里
Hot dog. Stuck in her throat.
没事了，过几天又活蹦乱跳啦
She'll be all right.
She'll be turning handsprings before you know it.
医生，谢谢你
Thank you, Doc.
不，孩子，谢谢你
No, son.
Thank you.
糟糕，你不能再回去了
Oh, my God. You can't go back.
你是不是不能回去了？ 没关系
Hey, it's all right.
对不起      真的没关系
I'm sorry. It's all right.
我最好快点回家
I best be getting on home
否则爱丽莎 以为我交女朋友去了
before Alicia begins to think I got a girlfriend.
嗨，医生
Hey, Doc.
医生，你医术高明
Good work, Doc.
你真行
Nice going, Doc.
我们会想你的
Going to miss you, Doc.
替我赢一场比赛好吗？
Win one for me one day, will you, boys?
Okay, Doc.
没问题      我们答应你
Yeah.
这些球员是什么时候来的
When did these ballplayers get here?
喂，菜鸟
Hey, rookie!
你真的很不错
You were good.
瑞，千万不要卖这个农场
Do not sell this farm, Ray. You got to keep this farm.
一定要保住它
You've had a rough day. Go inside and get something cold to drink.
你今天经历了不少事
一定要保住它
You've had a rough day. Go inside and get something cold to drink.
到屋里去喝点冷饮吧
Yeah. That's a good idea.
好主意
到屋里去喝点冷饮吧
Yeah. That's a good idea.
好主意
你千万别卖掉农场
Don't sell the farm, Ray.
瑞
Ray?
我们要休息了，明天见
We're going to call it a day.
See you tomorrow.
Okay.
好
要不要和我们一起去？
Hey, do you want to come with us?
当真？      不是你
You mean it?
No, not you.
是他
Him.
他？
Him? Come with you?
和你一起去？      到那边去
Out there.
那边有什么？ 你自己去发掘呀
What is out there?
Come and find out.
等等，球场是我盖的 为什么让他去
Wait a second. Why him?
I built this field. You wouldn't be here if it weren't for me.
如果不是我，你不可能在这里
Ray, I'm unattached. You have a family.
你还有家庭呀 我知道
I want to know what's out there.
可是我也想知道那边有什么
你还有家庭呀 我知道
I want to know what's out there.
可是我也想知道那边有什么
但是你没有被邀请呀
But you're not invited.
可是我也想知道那边有什么
但是你没有被邀请呀
But you're not invited.
没被邀请？这是什么意思？
Not invited? What do you mean I'm not invited?
那是我的玉米田 你们都是我的客人
That's my corn out there. You guys are guests in my corn.
我已经奉献得够多了
I've done everything I've been asked to do.
虽然许多吩咐我不明白 但仍照着去做
I didn't understand it, but I've done it.
从没问过我能得什么好处
I haven't once asked what's in it for me.
瑞，你想说什么？ 我想问“我能得到什么好处”
What are you saying?
I'm saying, "What's in it for me?"
难道你做这些全是为了自己
Is that why you did this?
For you?
你最好留在这里
I think you'd better stay here, Ray.
为什么？
Why?
他们选我是有原因的
There's a reason they chose me,
就像他们选中这个球场一样
just as there's a reason they chose this field.
为什么？      因为我是去采访
I gave that interview.
采访？你在说什么
What interview? What are you talking about?
我在说那座让你到 波士顿找我的艾柏特球场
The one about Ebbets Field, the one that sent you to Boston to find me.
你居然骗我
You lied to me.
别忘了你想绑架我
You were kidnapping me at the time. You lied.
你居然骗我 你还说你有枪
You said your finger was a gun.
这倒没错
That's a good point.
Ray.
你听我说
Listen to me, Ray. Listen to me.
那边有着不可思议的事
There is something out there,
如果我能有勇气去探讨
and if I have the courage to go through with this,
那将是个了不起的故事
what a story it'll make.
“赤脚乔杰克森来到爱荷华”
"Shoeless Joe Jackson comes to Iowa."
你真要写这些故事？
What? Are you going to write about it?
那当然
You bet I'll write about it.
你确实会写这些故事
You're going to write about it.
这是我的职业呀
That's what I do.
好
Good.
老公？
Honey?
老公，他到哪去？
Honey, where's he going?
他们邀泰瑞到那边去
Terry's been invited to go out with the others.
你觉得怎样？ 很蠢
How are you feeling, sweetheart?
Stupid.
那边？      对
You mean out?
Yeah.
未知的那边
Out.
哇，好棒
Far out.
我要全部细节
I want a full description.
好好照顾这个家
Take care of this family.
你要多加小心
Be careful.
再见
Bye.
怎么啦？
What?
你这个幽灵在笑什么？
What are you grinning at, you ghost?
“如果你盖了…”
"If you build it,
“他就会来”
"he will come."
喔，我的天
Oh, my God.
什么事？到底怎么了
What? What is it?
那是我父亲
It's my father.
“抚平他的伤痛”
"Ease his pain."
“到远方去”
"Go the distance."
原来是你
It was you.
不，瑞，是你自己
No, Ray.
It was you.
天呀
My God. I...
我只看到 几年后他被岁月折磨后的老态
I only saw him years later when he was worn down by life.
看看他现在…
Look at him.
这么年轻而且意气风发 眼里闪烁着青春的光芒
He's got his whole life in front of him, and I'm not even a glint in his eye.
我该怎么和他说呢？
What do I say to him?
你可以 先介绍他认识自己的孙女
Why don't you introduce him to his granddaughter?
嗨
Hi.
首先要谢谢你们盖这座球场
I just wanted to thank you folks for putting up this field,
让我们能来这里打球
letting us play here.
我叫约翰康斯拉
I'm John Kinsella.
我是瑞
I'm Ray.
这是我太太安妮
My wife Annie. Hi.
这是我女儿凯伦
This is my daughter Karin.
凯伦，这是我父…
Karin, this is my...
这是约翰
This is John.
嗨，约翰
Hi, John.
凯伦，你好
Hiya, Karin.
我们让你们俩去聊聊
Well, we're going to let you two talk.
如果真有那么多人要来 那可有得忙了
I mean, if all these people are going to come,
we got a lot of work to do.
非常高兴见到你
It was very nice meeting you.
是我的荣幸
Ma'am.
宝贝，我们走吧
Come on, hon.
你是个好捕手
You catch a good game.
谢谢
Thank you.
这里真美
It's so beautiful here.
对我来讲…
For me...
就像是梦幻成真一样
Well, for me it's like a dream come true.
我能问你一件事吗？
Can I ask you something?
这里是不是天堂？
Is... Is this heaven?
这是爱荷华
It's Iowa.
爱荷华？
Iowa?
对
Yeah.
我发誓这里真像天堂
I could have sworn it was heaven.
Is...
难道真有天堂吗？
Is there a heaven?
有的
Yeah.
就是让梦幻成真的地方
It's the place dreams come true.
那么这里或许真是天堂
Maybe this is heaven.
好吧…
Well...
瑞，晚安
Good night, Ray.
晚安，约翰
Good night, John.
嗨，爸爸？
Hey, Dad?
我们来玩接球，好吗？
You want to have a catch?
当然好
I'd like that.
剧终
献给天下的父母们
时间轴调整、中英字幕合并@致远淡泊